<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Jeff Fredrickson</title><link>https://ejeff.org/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Jeff Fredrickson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://ejeff.org/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bigger Notes</title><link>https://ejeff.org/projects/biggernotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ejeff.org/projects/biggernotes/</guid><description>As a Deaf person, I often use my phone to type out what I want to say to someone. I noticed that some folks were having a hard time reading the small text of Apple&amp;rsquo;s Notes app. The Notes app has an option to format text as a title to make it bigger; however, the app resets the text to normal after hitting Return, forcing me to reformat every line I type.</description></item><item><title>HELLO Q GA</title><link>https://ejeff.org/projects/helloqga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ejeff.org/projects/helloqga/</guid><description>Those of you who have used TDDs in the 80s and 90s will appreciate this.
One day, I noticed that the domain registrar Freenom was offering free .ga (Gabon) domain registration. So of course I had to do something TDD related.
Hint: After loading the website, start typing.</description></item><item><title>Minesweeper</title><link>https://ejeff.org/projects/minesweeper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ejeff.org/projects/minesweeper/</guid><description>I wanted to learn more about the HTML5 canvas when it was new, so I threw together this game over the weekend to utilize it. The game has some basic graphics, but no sprites or images were necessary; all graphics are drawn using HTML5 canvas 2D graphics methods.
The UI and game logic are completely separate, so it would be trivial to develop front ends for this game other than the HTML5 canvas version.</description></item><item><title>Operation: Miles for Smiles</title><link>https://ejeff.org/projects/milesforsmiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ejeff.org/projects/milesforsmiles/</guid><description>Operation: Miles for Smiles was a fundraising drive in which a group of bicyclists toured from California to Florida to raise funds for charity. They needed a website to promote their project and to allow donors and the public to track their progress across the country in real time.
The web team consisted of Scott Madsen and me. He designed the website&amp;rsquo;s look-and-feel, while I turned his design into HTML and wrote the back end.</description></item><item><title>Tactical Thrift</title><link>https://ejeff.org/projects/tactical-thrift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ejeff.org/projects/tactical-thrift/</guid><description>An Express web app demonstrating a Thrift Savings Plan investment model based on Mebane Faber&amp;rsquo;s paper, A Quantitative Approach to Tactical Asset Allocation. Faber describes an investment system that is based on comparing the current price of a fund to the 10-month simple moving average (SMA) of that fund, and making a buy/sell decision based on that comparison.
The app pulls fund data from the Thrift Savings Plan website and computes an investment position.</description></item><item><title>Ukiahi</title><link>https://ejeff.org/projects/ukiahi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ejeff.org/projects/ukiahi/</guid><description>I dusted off an old but intact copy of the Ukiah High School website that I found on the Internet Archive. A fellow student and I built this website back in 1997 when we were seniors.
Check out the source code for an awesome trip to the past. A &amp;ldquo;Netscape Comm. Corp.&amp;rdquo; DTD, check. Uppercase HTML tags, check. No CSS, check. Old school textured background, check. Visit counter, check!</description></item></channel></rss>